Guide to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Vertical Files: Subjects ALBA.VF.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: ALBA Subject Files, 1; 470732
  - Jewish Currents: Articles, 470982 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Daily Forward: Articles, 470981 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Labor and the Spanish Civil War, by Michael L. O'Flaherty, 470980 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Jewish Life: Articles, 470979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War (I), 470978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War (II), 470977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Bagon Paper, 470976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Bibliographies, 470975 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Bund (Poland), G. Pickhan, 470974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Butwin, J., 470973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Diamant, David, 470972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Lustiger Paper on German and Austrian Jews, 470971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Medem, Gina, 470970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Prago, Albert, 470969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Rockman, Alan S., M.A. Thesis, 470968 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Rothenberg, Joshua, Article on Botwin Company, 470967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Sichon, G. E. (Dr. Gabriel Ersler), 470966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Sugarman Project, 470965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Women, 470964 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Jews in the Spanish Civil War: Zaagsma, Gerben (articles and thesis), 470963 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, 470962 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Josef Stalin Battalion, 470961 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Journalism, 470960 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Journalists, 470959 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Juventudes Socialistas de Espana, 470958 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Kampfer und Freunde der Spanischen Republik 1936-1939 e.V., 470957 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Kansas Volunteers, 470956 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Komitee der Antifaschistischen Widerstandskampfer, 470955 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Kriegel, Frantisek, Dr., article by G. E. Sichon (Dr. Gabriel Ersler), 470954 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 12)
  - Labour Party (UK), 470953 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Labour Party Archives, Manchester: Inventory, 470952 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Latin American Volunteers, 470951 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Left Book Club, 470950 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Life Magazine: Spanish Civil War Coverage, 470949 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Ligue de Mutiles et Invalides de la Guerre d' Espagne: Temoignage, 470948 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - List of Dead, Wounded, and Missing (Mar-Apr 1938), 470947 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Lithuanian Volunteers, 470946 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Lovestoneites and POUM, 470945 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Luxembourg: Les Amis des Brigades Internationales, 470944 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Macedonian Volunteers, 470943 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Mackenzie Papineau Battalion, Americans in, 470942 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Mackenzie Papineau Battalion Veterans, 470941 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Madrid: Atrocities, 470940 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Madrid, Battle of, 470939 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Mail Service for International Brigade Volunteers in Spain, 470938 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Marine Cooks' and Stewards' Association, 470937 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Maritime Workers: Volunteers in Spain, 470936 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Masters Mates and Pilots of America, 470935 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - May Day 1938: "Viva el Ejercito Popular", 470934 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Medal Issued by Spain for International Brigades, 470933 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Medical Aspects of the Spanish Civil War; Bibliography compiled by Victor Berch, 470932 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy (later Medical Bureau...mittee to Aid Spanish Democracy), 470931 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy (later Medical Bureau...id Spanish Democracy) (Oversize), 470930 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 13)
  - Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy (later Medical Bureau...panish Democracy), Boston Branch, 470929 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Medical Services and Personnel, 470928 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Medical Services and Personnel: Lavoz de la Sanidad de la XV Division (photocopies), 470927 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Medical Services of the International Brigades in Spain, P. Kolarov, 470926 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Memorials, 470925 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Mexican Volunteers, 470924 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Mexico, 470923 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Michigan Volunteers, 470922 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Minnesota Volunteers, 470921 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Montana Volunteers, 470920 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Monuments, 470919 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Monuments: Madison, Wisconsin, 470918 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Monuments: New Hampshire, 470917 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Monuments: San Francisco, 470916 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Monuments / Sculpture: Shifrin, "David and Goliath" (Barcelona), 470915 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Morocco and Moroccans, 470914 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Musicians' Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 470913 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - National Caucus of Labor Committees: New Solidarity Article on Spanish Civil War, 470912 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - National Council for Evacuated Children, 470911 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - National History Day: ALBA Project, 470910 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Native American Volunteers [missing as of 8/2010], 470909 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Naval History (Spanish Civil War), 470908 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - New England Volunteers, 470907 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - New Jersey Volunteers, 470906 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - New Leader: Articles [missing as of 8/2010], 470905 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - New Mexico Volunteers, 470904 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - New School: Spanish Civil War Course, 470903 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - New York Joint Committee to Lift the Embargo, 470902 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - New York Public Library, 470901 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - New York State Volunteers, 470900 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - New York University: King Juan Carlos of Spain Center, 470899 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - New York University Spanish Civil War Course Syllabi, 470898 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - New York University Volunteers, 470897 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - New Zealand Volunteers, 470896 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Nicaragua, 470895 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 470894 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - North Axholme School: "Volunteers for Spain" series, 470893 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Nurses, 470892 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Ohio Volunteers, 470891 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ohio Volunteers (from J. Brandt Scrapbooks, ALBA 236), 470890 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Olympics, Barcelona, 1936, 470889 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Palestine/Israel Volunteers, 470888 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: Rare [Photocopies], circa 1937-1938; 498223 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Pamphlets: Southworth Collection, 470887 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Partido Obrero de Unificacin Marxista (POUM), 470886 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Partit Socialista Unificat de Catalunya, 470885 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Passport List (U.S. Senate Subcommittee Research, 1957), 470884 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Paterna: Executions, 470883 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Peruvian Volunteers, 470882 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Photographers: Chim (paper by Carole Naggon), 470881 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: ALBA Volunteers, Photocopies with Names ID'd, 470880 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Pittsburgh Volunteers, 470879 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Plaza de Oriente, 470878 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Poetry: Kenneth Rexroth, 470877 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Poetry: Spanish Civil War, 470876 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Polish Volunteers, 470875 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Portugal and the Franco Regime, 470874 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Portuguese Volunteers, 470873 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Postal History, 470872 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Posters, 470871 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Posters: Blythe Bennett Paper, 470870 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Prado Museum, Bombing Of, 470869 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Prison Camps, 470868 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Prisoners: General, 470867 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Prisoners: Italian Fascists, 470866 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Prisoners: Lists, from Archives in Salamanca and Avila, 470865 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Prisoners: Political (Franco Regime, 1960's-1970's), 470864 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Prisoners: Summary of Laws and Locations of Prison Archives in Spain, 470863 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Progressive Labor: "Lessons of People's War in Spain 1936-1939" (1974), 470862 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Puerto Rican Volunteers, 470861 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Puppet Theatre (Spain), 470860 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Radio Project: "Corpus Duende", 470859 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Radio Project: Peter Garvie, 470858 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Red Cross: Archives, 470857 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Refugees: France, 470856 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Renau Artwork (1938), 470855 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Repatriation of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Volunteers, 470854 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Romanian Volunteers, 470853 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Roosevelt Administration and the Spanish Civil War, 470852 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Russian Participation: Fascist, 470851 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Rutgers University: "Rutgers Remembers the Spanish Civil War ...dia," Student Publication (1978), 470850 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Sailing Lists, 470849 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Salamanca: Spanish Civil War Archives, 470848 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Santander, 470847 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Scottish Participation: Aid, 470846 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Scottish Volunteers, 470845 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Seattle Volunteers, 470844 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Seminar: "Americans in Spain, The International Brigade" (Northeast Illinois University, 1999), 470843 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Ships: Ciudad de Barcelona, Sinking of, 470842 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Ships: Erica Reed, 470841 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Sim (Rey Vila), 470840 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Smith Act Trials, List of Cases and Defendants (1948-1956), 470839 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 470838 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Socialist Appeal, 470837 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Socialist Party (U.S.), 470836 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Socors Roig de Catalunya, El, 470835 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Socorro Rojo Internacional, 470834 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Songs: Blythe Bennett Paper, 470833 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Songs: "'A Lyrical War': Songs of the Spanish Civil War," Laurence H. Birdsey, 470832 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Songs/Music, 470831 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Songs/Music (Oversize), 470830 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 14)
  - South Dakota Volunteers, 470829 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Southern Illinois University, 470828 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Soviet Union: Participation, 470827 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Spain: Campaign against U.S.-Madrid Treaty (1976), 470826 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Spain: Libraries and Archives, 470825 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Spain: Libraries and Archives (Albacete), 470824 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Spain: Maps, 470823 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Spain: Ministerio de Defensa Nacional - Blank certificates, 470822 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Spain: Politics, 470821 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Spain Today: Special Bulletins, 470820 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Spain: Trips by Veterans and Friends, 470819 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Spanish Childrens Relief Fund, 470818 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Spanish Citizenship, 470817 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Spanish Civil War: Acronyms, 470816 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Spanish Civil War: Archives and Libraries, 470815 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Spanish Civil War Center, Proposal for, 470814 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Spanish Civil War: Dissertations on, 470813 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Civil War: General, 470812 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Spanish Civil War Historical Society (VALB), 470811 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Spanish Civil War: Historiography and Bibliography, 470810 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Spanish Civil War Sites, 470809 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Spanish Civil War: "Turbulent Spain," National Geographic Magazine, 470808 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Spanish Democrats' Defense Fund, 470807 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Spanish Intellectual Aid (U.S.), 470806 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Spanish Medical Aid Committee (U.K.): Bulletins, 470805 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Spanish Nationalism: Alvarez Junco paper, 470804 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Spanish Prisoners Revue, 470803 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Spanish Refugee Aid, 470802 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Spanish Refugee Appeal, 470801 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Spanish Refugee Appeal (Oversize), 470800 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 16)
  - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign, 470799 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Spanish Republican Government in Exile, 470798 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board, 470797 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Support for Spanish Republic (U.S.), 470796 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Swedish Volunteers, 470795 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Swiss Volunteers, 470794 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Symposium: Literature of the Spanish Civil War: "Art and Ideology", 470793 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Symposium: Spanish Civil War: The Aftermath (Cambridge, MA, 1986), 470792 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Symposium: Tamiment Library (2007), 470791 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Symposium: "Unfulfilled Dream" (Spanish Institute, 1981), 470790 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Tampa, Florida: Spanish Civil War, 470789 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Tampa, Florida: Spanish Civil War (Oversize), 470788 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 15)
  - Television: "Angels of the Last Pure War " (Mary Lou Reker), 470787 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Television: "Between the Wars" (Eric Sevareid, 1978), 470786 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Television: Spanish Civil War Series (Granada Television), 470785 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Thaelmann Battalion, 470784 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Theatre: "The Artist Must Take Sides", 470783 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Theatre: General, 470782 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Theatre: "No Pasaran" (Santa Monica), 470781 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Theatre: "Red Bessie", 470780 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Theatre: "To Barcelona", 470779 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Theatre: Wolf, Roland," The Abraham Lincoln Brigade, A Play in Three Acts" (typescript), 470778 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Theatrical Programs: Spain (Oversize), 470777 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 17)
  - Tom Paine Brigade (Berkeley, CA), 470776 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Trade Union Relief for Spain, 470775 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Transmissions Units (Transmisiones), 470774 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Transport Workers, 470773 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Trotskyist Material, 470772 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - United American Spanish Aid Committee, 470771 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - United Spanish Societies to Aid Spain, 470770 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - United States Committee for a Democratic Spain, 470769 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - United States Foreign Policy and the Spanish Civil War, 470768 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - United States State Department Confidential Central Files: Spain: Internal Affairs, 1930-1939, 470767 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - University of California, 470766 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - University of California: San Diego, 470765 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - University of Illinois: Spanish Civil War Collections, 470764 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Valencia, 470763 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Veterans' Benefits for Abraham Lincoln Brigade Veterans (U.S. Congress), 470762 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Bulletin, 470761 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Bay Area Post, 470760 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Collections: U...ornia Berkeley, Bancroft Library, 470759 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Conference, 1969, 470758 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Dances and Balls, 470757 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): General (I), 470756 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): General (II), 470755 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Historical Commission, 470754 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): New York Post, 470753 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): San Diego Post, 470752 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Vietnam War (Oversize), 470751 (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 18)
  - Volkerbund (Geneva): Articles on the Spanish Civil War, 470750 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Volunteer for Liberty: History, 470749 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Volunteer for Liberty, Reprint Edition: Publicity Material, 470748 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Volunteer, The, 470747 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - War Resisters League, 470746 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Washington D.C. Friends of Spanish Democracy, 470745 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Wayne State University Volunteers, 470744 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Welsh Volunteers, 470743 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Westcoast Volunteer, 470742 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Wisconsin Volunteers, 470741 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "Wise and Foolish Dreamers" Exhibit, 554852 (Flat-file-folder 6 Right)
  - Women in the Spanish Civil War, 470740 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - World War II, Abraham Lincoln Brigade Veterans in, 470739 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Young Communist League: Challenge, 470738 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Young Defenders of Spanish Democracy, 470737 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Young People's Socialist League, 470736 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Yugoslav Medical Personnel, 470735 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Yugoslav Volunteers, 470734 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Yugoslav Volunteers: Udovicki Memoir, 470733 (Box 8, Folder 17)